Ivo Gomes

Senior Software Engineer



- ibbgomes@gmail.com
- Paga, Portugal
- k ivo-gomes.dev
- (7) ibbgomes
- in ibbgomes

PROFILE

Experienced software engineer with a strong passion for distributed systems, systems architecture, and security. With over five years of expertise in back-end development, I have had the privilege to contribute to significant projects, enriching my skills along the way. Recently, I completed my master's degree, further enhancing my knowledge and capabilities in the field.

HONORS

Fast Shining Award Nomination 12/2019

One of the four nominees for the Fast Shining Award in the second edition of Cegid Primavera Talent Awards. This recognition celebrates professionals who are early in their careers, highlighting their exceptional work and promising contributions.



Hashx ☑

A cross-platform, command-line interface, checksum utility.



Portuguese

English



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cegid

Senior Software Engineer

03/2022 - present

In my current role, I'm actively involved in managing the entire life cycle of a set of microservices. This includes their design, development, deployment, and continuous monitoring. These microservices are fundamental components for various cloud-based products, addressing cross-cutting concerns, and making a substantial impact on tens of thousands of daily users.

Software Engineer

11/2018 - 02/2022

Joined R&D, actively contributing to the development of a cloud-based platform at its core. Also worked on developing microservices, and these combined efforts accelerated and streamlined the development of cloud products across multiple teams in the organization.

Curricular Internship

08/2018 - 09/2018

Designed and implemented a middleware solution, enabling seamless integration between two internal information systems.

Summer Internship

06/2017 - 09/2017

Migrated a automated testing infrastructure to a modern technology stack, aligning it with current industry practices.

Buzina - Negócios Digitais

Full-stack Developer

05/2016 - 02/2017

Continued the development and enhancement of a web application initially conceived during a curricular internship.

Buzina - Negócios Digitais

Curricular Internship

04/2015 - 07/2015

Designed and developed a comprehensive web application, specifically aimed at managing small businesses efficiently.

EDUCATION

Master in Computer Science & Engineering

Polytechnic Institute of Cávado and Ave

10/2019 - 09/2023

Developed a thesis introducing a scalability-oriented webhooks architecture that enhanced and expanded upon the existing approaches documented in the literature.

Bachelor in Computer Science & Engineering

Polytechnic Institute of Cávado and Ave

09/2015 - 10/2018

Served as the elected representative for the course during the period of 2016-2017.

Associate in Networks & Systems Administration

Polytechnic Institute of Cávado and Ave

10/2014 - 07/2015

